DAMOLA TAIWO

Web: https://github.com/Deejarh ◆ **LinkedIn:** https://shorturl.at/diKQ2

Portfolio - https://badmus-damola-taiwo.netlify.app/

Professional Summary

I am a highly talented fullstack with over four years of invaluable experience in the fintech/credit Industry, consistently delivering exceptional user experiences for a range of web applications with a strong focus on performance, accessibility, and responsiveness. I have successfully harnessed an impressive array of cutting-edge technologies, including JavaScript, Typescript, VueJs, NuxtJs, React, NextJs, NodeJs, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, REST, Bash, Tailwind CSS, and HTML to fulfill complex functional requirements across a diverse spectrum of Fintech/credit products.

Work history

Fullstack Engineer (Remote), 01/2022 - Current

Torus Mara - Delaware, USA- Remote

Torus Mara provides modern financial services for global institutions, corporations, and SMEs across emerging markets. My accomplishments include the following:

- Led the end-to-end development and successful launch of Omni, a payment platform. Managed frontend and backend development, ensuring a seamless and secure payment experience via cryptocurrency using a wallet connect SDK and fiat payments through third-party SDK (Collect) integration.
- Spearheaded the creation of an Admin dashboard, streamlining business data management and empowering administrators with oversight of sign-ups, account activation/deactivation, and efficient management of pending KYCs, utilizing Test-Driven Development (TDD) with Cypress to ensure robust and reliable functionality.
- Developed a versatile FX terminal enabling two-way transactions supporting NGN and GHS to USD, along with crypto assets like USDT. The terminal facilitates fee computation and real-time exchange rate calculations. Currently servicing over 32 registered businesses, with integrated admin tracking via the dashboard to monitor transaction statuses seamlessly.
- Developed a 7-step KYC form for new businesses' compliance, allowing progress saving and continuation. Included seamless biometric verification using a third-party integration, smoothly transitioning users to the next form step upon completion.
- Created an onboarding guide on Confluence for new engineers highlighting setup and configuration instructions using our single sign-on Identity verification tool. The guide also includes running a local instance of our web application.

Tech stack: Javascript, Typescript, VueJs(2 & 3), NuxtJs, React, NestJs, Node, PostgreSQL, RestAPI, Vuetify, Gsap, Vuex, TailwindCss, HTML, SASS, Git, Jest, Cypress, Github Action (CI/CD), Bash, Sentry, Figma, Mixpanel (Event tracking), Grafana, Kibana, AWS.

Frontend Engineer, 07/2021 - 12/2021

BFREE - Lagos, Nigeria

BFREE is a credit management company that focuses on consumers' financial health by building products that make collection processes in Africa more scalable, efficient, and user-friendly. My accomplishments include the following:

• Improved data security by implementing a role-based access control (RBAC) system in the CRM, resulting

in a 100% reduction in unauthorized data access

- Boosted agent productivity by 2x through the implementation of a notification system that alerted agents about newly assigned customers in the CRM
- Streamlined customer payment evidence processing by introducing a View/Download feature in the CRM, resulting in a 100% decrease in the time and cost required for manual uploads
- Collaborated with a team of 3 frontend developers to enhance the user experience of the CRM by incorporating frequently used features and implementing privacy measures, leading to a 30% increase in monthly revenue
- Strengthened the stability of the CRM application by developing Jest tests for utility functions, minimizing the risk of breaking changes when new features are added.
- Performed manual and automated testing to ensure stability across range of devices and browsers.

Tech stack: Vue2, Javascript, GraphQl, Vuetify, HTML, CSS, Jest, Git, AWS.

Frontend Engineer Intern, 01/2021 - 06/2021

BFREE - Lagos, Nigeria

- Collaborated with a team of two to develop the BFREE website, enhancing brand visibility and attracting potential customers
- Contributed to building and maintaining the company's Self-service portal, enabling customers to effortlessly manage their loan portfolio
- Implemented new features and maintained the company's CRM system within a team, improving customer relationship management and streamlining internal processes.

Tech stack: Vue2, Javascript, GraphQl, Vuetify, HTML, CSS, Git.

Software development bootcamp, 01/2020 - 12/2020

Self-Directed with Mentor - Lagos

- Gained foundational frontend development skills in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript through mentorship, applying knowledge to practical projects.
- Enhanced learning through FreeCodeCamp, earning a certification and building additional projects to solidify skills.

	— Skills —			
 JavaScript/Typescript 	• CSS/Tailwind CSS			
• Vue/NuxtJs	 Agile Methodologies (Scrum) 			
• React/NextJs	• Cypress			
• GraphQL	• Jest			
• Git	• SQL			
• REST	• Bash			
• HTML5	• Figma			
	- Education -			
BSc : Computer Engineering, 11/2019 Obafemi Awolowo University - Ile-Ife Ife				
	- Languages			
English				
Fluent				

\sim				
Cert	ITI	<i>C</i> ' ለገ	$\Gamma \mathbf{I}$	NIC

- Certified Internet Web Professional
- Hackerrank Javascript